Sachin Saxena 1389, First Floor Sector 68

Mohali Pin 160062

E-mail: sachinsaxena1996@gmail.com

<u>sachinsaxena08@yahoo.co.in</u> Mobile: 9820416174, 7678147566

SUMMARY

Worked as a Senior Software Engineer with WaterMark Insights. I have 9+ years of experience, which mainly involves web application development with "Ruby on Rails" for verticals like 'Social Networking', 'Banking', 'Finance', 'Hospitality Domain'. I have proven skills in web application development for developing complex and real time solutions as per the client's requirements. I have ability to advocate Rails best practices, TDD/BDD, Application Security, Code quality, Code Refactoring, Application performance improvement, Code Review, Report creation for various perspectives for improvement of rails application.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

My main area of experience has been working on Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Jquery, Ajax, HTML, AngularJS, Bootstrap & C.

Sprylogic Ltd.

Premco Global Ltd.

Arrk Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Incedo Inc

News Print Group Pvt. Ltd.

MotherSon Sumi Infotech

WaterMark Insights

19 June 2009 to 14 Jan 2013

16 Jan 2013 to 28 June 2014

1 Jan 2015 to 6 Oct 2016

10 Oct 2016 to 27 June 2017

18 Sep 2017 to 28 Feb 2018

1 March 2018 to 30 Sept 2018

21 Jan 2019 to 3 Dec 2019

QUALIFICATION

- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science from RGPV, technical university of M.P in 2005-2009 with 68%.
- HSC passed out in 2004 from St. Joseph's Convent H.S.S, Khandwa under M.P.
 Board with 78.2%.
- SSC passed out in 2002 from St. Joseph's Convent H.S.S, Khandwa under M.P.
 Board with 82.6%.

SKILLS

Languages
 Ruby on Rails, Rspec, Java, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax,

Jquery, Bootstrap, Angular JS, ReactJs, Redux

Databases Postgres, Redis, MySQL, SQL Server 2005.

Web/app Server Webrick, Thin, Apache, Phusion Passenger, Puma.

• SCM tools Svn, Git, Bitbucket.

Deployment Tool Heroku, Capistrano.

• Operating Systems Windows, Ubuntu, Centos, Linux.

Project worked on in WaterMark Insights

Project title: Via

Role: SSE

Details: Via is watermark product used for Student Assesment. ePortfolios give students many ways to deepen their learning. They can track their progress across experiences and over time, reflect on what they've learned, showcase their accomplishments, and easily share their work with others.

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, Mongodb, Rspec, Slack, github, Jira, AWS S3,

ReactJs with Redux, AngularJS, Jasmine, Mocha, Karma

Duration: 21 Jan 2019 to 3 Dec 2019.

Project worked on in MotherSon Sumi infotech

Project title: Salido **Role:** Project Lead

Details: Salido is a restaurant O.S. It's a product which enables restaurants to manage there orders, payments and entire operations. It provides consumers with digital payment options like levelup.

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, MySql, Rspec, Slack, Code Climate, github, Jira, postgres, AWS S3.

Duration: 1 March 2018 to 30 Sept 2018.

Project worked on in News Print Pvt Ltd.

Project title: WOP
Role: Team Lead

Details: WOP is a web based application used by News Print's clients for order processing. WOP application is used across the globe by clients to place and track their orders. WOP works in synchronization with a Beper application. Beper is a desktop application used in the supply chain. WOP accepts orders via ETL process and also via synchronization with beper.

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, AngularJs, MySql, Newrelic, Rspec, Slack, Code Climate, github, Jira.

Duration: 18 Sept 2017 to 28 Feb 2018.

Project worked on in Incedo Inc

Project title: Sesac-api

Client: Sesac

Role: Senior Software Engineer

Details: SESAC, originally the "Society of European Stage Authors and Composers" is a performance-rights organization (PRO) in the United States. Based in Nashville, Tennessee, SESAC deals with all aspects of the business, from creation to licensing and administration. Sesac-api is rack based app which provides the Rest Api to the front End which is built in Angular Js. It is music licensing software which enables maintaining license and royalty of the authors.

Technologies used: Ruby, MySql, Postgres 9.4, Newrelic, Rspec, Slack, Code Climate,

github, Jira.

Duration: 10 Oct 2016 to 27 June 2017.

Project worked on in Arrk Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Project title: Union cloud

Client: National Union of Students (NUS)

Role: Senior Software Engineer

Details: The National Union of Students of the United Kingdom (NUS) is a confederation of student's unions in the United Kingdom. Around 600 student's unions are in membership, accounting for more than 95 per cent of all higher and further education unions in the UK. Union Cloud is the NUS's digital platform, providing the scalability to potentially connect with and communicate to the entire UK student population of around 7 million people. It has given NUS the potential to turn a diverse group of individual student union organizations into a cohesive and connected community.

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, Jquery, Javascript, Ajax, Css, HTML5, Redis, Postgres 9.4, Newrelic, Rspec, bootstrap, AWS S3, Linux O.S.

Duration: 1 Jan 2015 to 6 Oct 2016.

Project title: UWE

Client: University of the West of England (UWE)

Role: Senior Software Engineer

Details: UWE Bristol is a modern university, offering a wide range of highly respected courses and employment-enhancing opportunities – in one of the UK's most vibrant cities. UWE is a well-established university, with over 27,000 students, 250,000 alumni and 3,000 staff. Students come to study with UWE from all over the UK, as well as from 140 different countries around the world, making this a diverse and interesting place to come and study. The UWE application enables the students to view, apply and process their applications for various courses offered by UWE. It also enables the UWE staff to evaluate and process the student's course applications.

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, AngularJs, Bootstrap3, HTML5, Redis, Capistrano,

Git.

Duration: 1 August 2016 to 6 Oct 2016.

PROJECT WORKED ON IN PREMCO GLOBAL LTD.

PROJECT TITLE: Onspot

Client: Jute Commission of India **DURATION**: Jan 2013 to June 2014

Roles: Software developer.

Technology Used: Ruby on Rails (3.2.11), Javascript, Ajax and MySQL, Bulk SMS

HTTP API, Geocoder, Google Earth API.

DETAILS: Onspot is an application for product authentication, tracking & tracing for retail supply chain logistics right from the manufacturer to the end consumer. It provides following solutions:

- Product Tracking Solution
- Brand Security System
- Loss Prevention
- Retail & Future Market Analysis

PROJECT WORKED ON IN SPRYLOGIC LTD.

PROJECT TITLE: DQMS (Dynamic queue management system)

CLIENT: ICICI, PNB

DURATION: June 2009 to Jan 2013

Roles: Software developer.

Technology Used: Ruby on Rails (1.2.3), Javascript, Ajax and MySQL,

SOL Server 2005, Ubuntu OS.

DETAILS: DQMS is a dynamic queue management system used for efficiently serving customers in banks. DQMS are Ubuntu O.S system in banks with user interface (Front End for customers) designed in Java. The customer can select his customer-type and service type and receives a token based on queuing logic. The application on teller's system is Rails application through which customer is served. There are features like "Token Pulling" & "Token Pushing" to manage queues. The records of the tokens from all branches of the Bank are sent to a **CMT** (Central Monitoring Tool) via TCP/IP protocol using Socket Programming. CMT is also capable of updating service-type across multiple remote DQMS.

AWARDS RECEIVED

- Received "Certificate of Appreciation" from UK Client "NUS (National Union of Students)".
- Received scholarship twice from "Madhya Pradesh Board" for securing maximum marks in Sanskrit.
- Received scholarship from "All India Kayastha Association" for securing 82.6% in 10th Board.
- Received 'A' certificate in N.C.C under 36-MP Battalion.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 23 September 1985 Father's Name: Dr. Ajay Saxena Mother's Name: Smt. Kusum Saxena

Nationality: Indian Marital Status: Married

Languages known: English, Hindi, Sanskrit.

Hobbies: Watching News Channels, Playing Chess.

DATE: PLACE: (Er. SACHIN SAXENA)